WILLIAM METCALF Software Developer

ABOUT ME

Working on teams where my work has a direct positive impact is something that I have always valued. During my time in the United States Air Force, I worked as a software developer, solving problems on government and military applications using HTML, CSS, JAVA, and JavaScript. Upon leaving the military, I decided to expand my knowledge in development and learn more current and full stack technologies through Nashville Software School. My goal is to contribute to applications that positively impact and support users health and wellness.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell: 918-630-9012

https://github.com/WilliamMetcalf-37

SKILLS

- HTML5 Java
 - CSS • Git
 - JavaScript React.js

Agile

SQL

C#/.Net

 Entity Identity

AWARDS

- Joint Service Achievement Medal, 2017
- Army Achievement Medal, 2017
- · Global War on Terrorism Expeditionary Medal, 2017
- Air Force Organizational Excellence Medal, 2014
- Global War on Terrorism Service Medal, 2012
- National Defense Service Medal, 2012

EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

Software Developer

- Intensive, full-time 6 month Full-Stack software development program learning technologies through the creation of applications in group and individual settings
- HTML 5/ CSS3 Javascript/REACT Front-End
- C#/.Net Back-End

QuikTrip

Nov 2018-May 2019

Nov 2019-May 2020

Assistant Manager

- Delivered excellent customer service by greeting and assisting each customer. Addressed customer inquiries and resolved complaints.
- Stocked and restocked inventory when shipments were received. Reorganized the sales floor to meet company demands.

United States Air Force

2012-2018

Software Developer

- Worked in Agile development team to build a batch mode application for Combat Ammunition Systems. System built with HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JS, JQuery and Microsoft Access Database.
- Lead programmer for Combat Ammunition System 3.0 Help screens

Camp Lemonnier, Djibouti, Africa

Oct 2016 - May 2017

SharePoint Administrator

- Managed account privileges for 4.5K active users on military installation
- Reformed Mission Travel tracking system, combining 4 step process down to 1, reducing average processing time to 1 day from 3 days. Forms built with Microsoft InfoPath.

University of Tulsa

2011-2012

Petroleum Engineering Research Technician

· Built, maintained and operated petro-chemical test equipment for industry funded programs at the University of Tulsa.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Nov 2019-May 2020

Certificate, Software Development

PROJECTS

Projects

Squad Up

Social media style app for users to connect with other users and to assist in organizing rave events. App allows users to add and remove friends, send direct messages to friends, organize groups of friends, and establish group chats. Users can also access an external API to search for rave events.

- Full CRUD application created to connect users created utilizing HTML, JavaScript, React, React Router, and API fetch calls to internal and external API's/JSON servers
- Utilized CSS for styling

DiabeticAide

Diabetic patient data logging app that allows users to easily store their blood sugar readings. Patients can have helpers that are allowed to input data for the patient. Helpers also have a reminder button to send a reminder text to their phone.

- Utilized C#/.net , MVC, Entity and Identity frameworks with SQLEXPRESS database
- Used Twilio REST API for sending text messages and Highcharts for building graphs for patient data